Kevin Hornschemeier

- 2327 Pleasant Meadows Dr Batavia, OH 45103
- khornschemeier@gmail.com
- 513-317-6430
- http://khornschemeier.com
- https://github.com/khornschemeier

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer with a computer science background in C/C++, algorithms, and data structures, and over 10 years of full-stack web development experience. I also have experience in QA, analytics, and SEO.

I am always learning new things and can adapt quickly to new technologies. I like collaborating with other engineers who like to solve tough problems and take pride in their work. I also like working for companies who hire good talent, will listen to the ideas and input from all their employees, and truly care about having a good culture and working environment.

SKILLS

- HTML
- LESS
- jQuery
- MySQL
- AJAX
- REST
- C

- CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP
- Git
- JSON
- Responsive Design
- C++

EXPERIENCE

LamsonEnia Design

12 / 2012 - Present

Director of Technology

I manage all aspects of the technical stack for a design and marketing agency. I maintain existing clients' sites, build new sites, and manage a few remote Flash developers for a large site. I am also building the technical architecture for an in-house CMS to be used for future client sites.

Tellus 01 / 2012 - 12 / 2012

Lead Web Developer

A design and marketing agency where I led the development. I managed existing client sites, built new sites, and led our QA and e-commerce initiatives. I also helped out on strategy, SEO, and analytics reports.

Venturepax.com

01 / 2011 - 01 / 2012

Director of Web Technology

A Cincinnati start-up where I was brought on as the technical co-founder. The site allowed users to search for outdoor activities based on the user's location and the specific activity they were looking to do. Content was curated from multiple sources including an outdoor book publisher, publicly available content, and user submitted content. Initially I helped maintain and expand the existing version of the site and managed an outside source for our first mobile app. When redesigning the experience, I took over the architecture and planning for the technology stack. I rebuilt the site from the ground up with a new database schema,

framework, API, and functionality. An iPhone developer was brought on who I coordinated with on our new mobile app.

Textbook Revolt

11 / 2007 - 01 / 2011

Co-founder, Web Developer

A site I co-founded and built. We began addressing the problem of high priced textbooks by experimenting with a completely free college textbook exchange. Students could list the textbooks they were done with and view available textbooks from other students to create exchanges. The site received many accolades from students who were previously dissatisfied with the other options available to them. As a result, students from over 1,300 schools nationwide joined and posted over \$1,000,000 in college textbooks. We eventually sold the site.

Strata-G Communications

08 / 2007 - 12 / 2010

Web Developer

A design and marketing agency where I managed existing client sites, built new sites, and helped with analytics and SEO.

FotoFlix

02 / 2006 - 08 / 2007

Lead Web Developer

A photo sharing and managing application with the unique ability to create slideshows and add graphical enhancements on top of them. When hired, I helped the technical co-founder with building a new site from the ground up. I was also integral in building out the forums and helped with most of the functionality of the site. The site had approximately 1 million uploaded photos and 10,000 users before having to be shut down due to lack of funding.

EDUCATION

Nova Southeastern University

2004 - 2006

B.S. CIS , Computer Information Systems

University of Cincinnati

Computer Science

2000 - 2004